Hello and welcome to Real easyy English where we have real conversations in easyy English to help you learn I'm Georgie and I'm Beckcker,
You can find a video version of this podcast on our website and test yourself with a worksheet on BBClearningenglish.com. .
Hello Beckcca how are you I'm really well, Thank you Georgie, How about yourself, Yes, I'm good thank you you're having a busy week It has been a little bit busy but also
Quite fun how about yours me too I've had a busy week but it's going well and becca today we're talking about work we're going to talk about what we're good at
At work and also what we do when things go wrong okay so what do you.
Like about work I like that we have different tasks to do in the day and some of them are creative and then
Other tasks you really need to kind of. Put more thought and focus into Becca, do you ever find work stressful,
Of course, I think that you will find work stressful at some point.
During your your job or your career, um yeah, I think if I haven't planned things well, if I haven't done the preparation well.
Then I find things a bit stressful yeah about yourself yeah me too when we have lots of projects as well,
I feel like when we have a lot of things going on it can be stressful to kind of, Juggle different tasks.
And when we need to publish a new podcast or a new video series it can be there can be a lot of pressure to get things done So would you say
That you're someone.
Who get stressed easily at work because you seem to be quite calm all the time Yeah, no, I don't actually get too stressed very often even when there's a bit of pressure at work.
I tend to stay quite calm I always just think there's no point in worrying worrying doesn't actually fix the issues and you can only
Do what you can do so.
Yeah, I tend to stay quite relaxed what about you do you get quite stressed or yeah, as I previously mentioned, I think if.
I'm usually quite an organised person, but you know, there are some times where I feel a bit disorganised and if I don't prepare,
I find myself in stressful situations and, Um, I might start feeling a bit nervous,
Especially as time gets closer to completing something, I really don't like having things late.
Yeah, not just in work, but in my general life, so you get nervous if you're not feeling organized, but are you good at being organized Yes, if I write things down then I,
Tend to stay organize.
It's likely that I won't feel very stress.
Can I can start to relax a bit when I know that.
You know, I've tipped things off my list do you right to do list, I do, I do write to do list and that can be really helpful and kind of keep calm because you you have your Whole plan.
On a page that you can see and you can kind of know where you are in your week, which is really helpful.
Yeah, what happens when things go wrong at work.
What how do you kind of. How do you deal with these situations?
I've only been here for a little while in comparison to yourself and the rest of the team and I feel really thankful that you're
Very supportive, so if I do have something that I haven't quite finished or I'm not really sure what I'm doing with it or it just goes completely
Wrong, then I feel that I can come to yourself or any of the team to ask for a little bit of help.
Or guided oh that's good, I don't think anything's gone completely wrong since you've been here, not yet audio listeners, fingers crossed fingers.
Okay, let's recap the language we heard during the conversation, starting with stress now stress is a feeling of worry usually caused by a particular situation
And you can describe a person as being stressed and that is the feeling.
Of having stress, and we can also say stressful, which describes the situation.
We also had calm, and that's when you don't feel stressed or worried about something, for example.
Georgie is always very calm at work.
We also heard nervous, which describes someone who worries a lot.
We had organized someone who is organized, plans very well and prepares very well.
The opposite of organ is disorganised and we heard supportive and if someone is supportive, they help other people.
That's it for this episode of Real easyy English we'll be back next week with another easy English conversation and if you want more easy English head to our website to try some of our
Other easy series, for example the London Lettter Challenge.
Go to our website, BBC learningningenglish dot com.
Good for now, bye.